[
  {
    "question": "While cruising down what river in 1542 was Francisco de Orellana attacked by female warriors that gave it its name?",
    "right_answer": "Amazon",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Congo",
      "Yangtze",
      "Mississippi"
    ],
    "category": "history",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "Which conjunction follows 'fa' in the lyric of a song from 'The Sound of Music'?",
    "right_answer": "So",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "La",
      "Do",
      "Mi"
    ],
    "category": "music",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of pasta is pappardelle?",
    "right_answer": "Ribbon pasta",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Stuffed pasta",
      "Tubular pasta",
      "Shaped pasta"
    ],
    "category": "food_and_drink",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "Which actress has played roles in both X-Men: Days of Future Past and Die Another Day?",
    "right_answer": "Halle Berry",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Frances Fisher",
      "Salma Hayek",
      "Rachel Weisz"
    ],
    "category": "film_and_tv",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Cardiology the study of?",
    "right_answer": "The heart",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Knots",
      "Japanese people",
      "Poker"
    ],
    "category": "science",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "Which author wrote 'The Great Gatsby'?",
    "right_answer": "F. Scott Fitzgerald",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Robert A. Heinlein",
      "James Fenimore Cooper",
      "Donna Leon"
    ],
    "category": "arts_and_literature",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of a snake-like fish that is often used in sushi?",
    "right_answer": "Eel",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Salmon",
      "Tuna",
      "Octopus"
    ],
    "category": "food_and_drink",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "Which French electronica duo released the song 'Harder, Better, Faster, Stronger'?",
    "right_answer": "Daft Punk",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Gong",
      "Indochine",
      "Nouvelle Vague"
    ],
    "category": "music",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the common name for sodium chloride?",
    "right_answer": "Table Salt",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "QuickSilver",
      "Baking Soda",
      "Cream of tartar"
    ],
    "category": "science",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "'Hello Moto' is a slogan associated with which communications brand?",
    "right_answer": "Motorola",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Sony",
      "Samsung",
      "Nokia"
    ],
    "category": "society_and_culture",
    "difficulty": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the cocktail called, that consists of four parts of tequila to two parts of lemon or limejuice?",
    "right_answer": "Margarita ",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Martini",
      "Bloody Mary",
      "Tequila Sunrise"
    ],
    "category": "food_and_drink",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the smallest country in the world?",
    "right_answer": "Vatican City",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Monaco",
      "Nauru",
      "San Marino"
    ],
    "category": "geography",
    "difficulty": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "Where would you find the city of Vancouver?",
    "right_answer": "Canada",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Australia",
      "New Zealand",
      "United States"
    ],
    "category": "geography",
    "difficulty": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these dishes is most associated with Brazil?",
    "right_answer": "Feijoada",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Poutine",
      "Couscous",
      "Ambuyat"
    ],
    "category": "food_and_drink",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "Which motoring brand is associated with the marketing slogan 'The Power of Dreams'?",
    "right_answer": "Honda",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Mazda",
      "Jaguar",
      "Aston Martin"
    ],
    "category": "society_and_culture",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A car designer and driver battle to build a revolutionary race car.'",
    "right_answer": "Le Mans '66",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Dr. Strangelove or: How I Learned to Stop Worrying and Love the Bomb",
      "Ratatouille",
      "Downfall"
    ],
    "category": "film_and_tv",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Oscar Winning Actor Played Scrooge In \"The Muppet Christmas Carol\"?",
    "right_answer": "Michael Caine",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Patrick Stewart",
      "Christopher Lee",
      "Daniel Day Lewis"
    ],
    "category": "film_and_tv",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the Islamic holy book?",
    "right_answer": "Quran",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Bible",
      "Torah",
      "Gita"
    ],
    "category": "society_and_culture",
    "difficulty": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "What type of instrument is a flute?",
    "right_answer": "Woodwind",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Stringed",
      "Percussion",
      "Brass"
    ],
    "category": "music",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the plot of the movie Raiders of the Lost Ark?",
    "right_answer": "An archaeologist is hired by the government to find the Ark of the Covenant.",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "On a journey to find the cure for a curse, a boy finds himself in the middle of a war.",
      "A Tramp struggles to live in modern industrial society with the help of a young homeless woman.",
      "A 12-year-old is taken in by a professional assassin after her family is murdered."
    ],
    "category": "film_and_tv",
    "difficulty": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the term given to the act of lying in court?",
    "right_answer": "Perjury",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Obstruction",
      "Suborning",
      "Fraud"
    ],
    "category": "society_and_culture",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "Which New York island was bought by the Dutch in 1626 and is named after the Indian tribe who lived there?",
    "right_answer": "Manhattan",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Long Island",
      "Staten Island",
      "Coney Island"
    ],
    "category": "history",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "What is cryptology the study of?",
    "right_answer": "How to encode and decode secret messages",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Animal diseases",
      "Sacred texts",
      "Burial grounds"
    ],
    "category": "science",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "Prague is the capital city of which country?",
    "right_answer": "Czechia",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Armenia",
      "Botswana",
      "Portugal"
    ],
    "category": "geography",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "Which substance has the chemical formula NaOH?",
    "right_answer": "Sodium Hydroxide",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Potassium Sulfate",
      "Nitrogen Chloride",
      "Carbon Iodine"
    ],
    "category": "science",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "What Would You Traditionally 'Bob' For At Halloween?",
    "right_answer": "Apples",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Bananas",
      "Cherries",
      "Carrots"
    ],
    "category": "society_and_culture",
    "difficulty": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the capital city of The United Kingdom?",
    "right_answer": "London",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Manchester",
      "Birmingham",
      "Winchester"
    ],
    "category": "geography",
    "difficulty": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the plot of the movie Rush?",
    "right_answer": "The merciless rivalry between Formula One rivals James Hunt and Niki Lauda.",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "The lives of mob hitmen, a boxer, a gangster and his wife, and a pair of bandits intertwine in four tales.",
      "A stand-up comedian embarks on a downward spiral that leads to the creation of an iconic villain.",
      "An Army officer serving in Vietnam is tasked with assassinating a renegade Special Forces Colonel."
    ],
    "category": "film_and_tv",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the natural wonder that stretches over 1,250 miles off the east coast of Australia?",
    "right_answer": "The Great Barrier Reef",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "The Northern Lights",
      "The Galapagos Islands",
      "The Mariana Trench"
    ],
    "category": "geography",
    "difficulty": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of the first artificial satellite to be launched into space?",
    "right_answer": "Sputnik",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Endeavour",
      "Landsat",
      "Terra"
    ],
    "category": "history",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the word for a young turtle?",
    "right_answer": "A Hatchling",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "A Piglet",
      "A Maggot",
      "A Lamb"
    ],
    "category": "science",
    "difficulty": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these quotes is from the film 'The Silence of the Lambs'?",
    "right_answer": "\"A census taker once tried to test me. I ate his liver with some fava beans and a nice Chianti.\"",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "\"Attica! Attica!\"",
      "\"Chewie, we’re home.\"",
      "\"What is this? A center for ants? How can we be expected to teach children to learn how to read…if they can’t even fit inside the building?\""
    ],
    "category": "film_and_tv",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the classic board game where players must be the first to send all four of their pieces all the way round a board?",
    "right_answer": "Trouble",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Life",
      "Risk",
      "Checkers"
    ],
    "category": "sport_and_leisure",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the term for a tax on selling goods or services?",
    "right_answer": "Sales Tax",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Income Tax",
      "Property Tax",
      "Land Tax"
    ],
    "category": "society_and_culture",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1988, Bobby Fischer invented a new type of clock that has since become widely used in which board game?",
    "right_answer": "Chess",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Checkers",
      "Backgammon",
      "Go"
    ],
    "category": "sport_and_leisure",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Disease Of The Liver Is Associated With Alcoholism?",
    "right_answer": "Cirrhosis",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Hepatitis",
      "Scurvy",
      "Meningitis"
    ],
    "category": "science",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "A male chicken is known as what?",
    "right_answer": "A Rooster",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "A Buck",
      "A Dog",
      "A Ram"
    ],
    "category": "science",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "What Shakespearean king was actually king of Scotland for 17 years?",
    "right_answer": "Macbeth",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Lear",
      "Hamlet",
      "Richard III"
    ],
    "category": "history",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "In which country would you find the Statue of Liberty?",
    "right_answer": "USA",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Brazil",
      "Spain",
      "The UK"
    ],
    "category": "geography",
    "difficulty": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "When did the scientist Tim Berners-Lee invent the World Wide Web?",
    "right_answer": "1989",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "1984",
      "1994",
      "1999"
    ],
    "category": "history",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "Which English rock band released the song 'Let It Be'?",
    "right_answer": "The Beatles",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Deep Purple",
      "Feeder",
      "Uriah Heep"
    ],
    "category": "music",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the lead singer of the Cure?",
    "right_answer": "Robert Smith",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Thomas Lawrence",
      "John Martin",
      "Jack Austin"
    ],
    "category": "music",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the flag of Malaysia look like?",
    "right_answer": "14 horizontal stripes of red and white, with a blue square in the top left containing a yellow crescent and star.",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Three equal horizontal bands of yellow green and red.",
      "White with a large red disk in the center.",
      "Blue with a red cross outlined in white extending to the edges."
    ],
    "category": "geography",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "What do the letters 'TBH' mean on internet chats?",
    "right_answer": "To Be Honest",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Two Big Heads",
      "The Best Hope",
      "This Brilliant Human"
    ],
    "category": "society_and_culture",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Record Breaking Video Game Character Made It's Debut in May 1980?",
    "right_answer": "Pac-Man",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Sonic The Hedgehog",
      "Mario",
      "Lara Croft"
    ],
    "category": "sport_and_leisure",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "In which country would you find the terracotta warriors?",
    "right_answer": "China",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Japan",
      "Thailand",
      "India"
    ],
    "category": "geography",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "Which stout is Dublin world-famous for?",
    "right_answer": "Guinness ",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Porters",
      "Doogals",
      "Old Black"
    ],
    "category": "food_and_drink",
    "difficulty": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "What Is The Worlds Largest Hot Desert?",
    "right_answer": "The Sahara ",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "The Gobi",
      "The Mojave",
      "The Arabian"
    ],
    "category": "geography",
    "difficulty": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "What are Petrol, Naphta, Kerosine, Diesel and Oil?",
    "right_answer": "Hydrocarbons",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Gases",
      "Petroleum Spirits",
      "Methylated Spirits"
    ],
    "category": "science",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "Which film contains the character 'Lloyd Dobler'?",
    "right_answer": "Say Anything...",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "The Adventures of Robin Hood",
      "The Silence of the Lambs",
      "The Treasure of the Sierra Madre"
    ],
    "category": "film_and_tv",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the capital city of Germany?",
    "right_answer": "Berlin",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Munich",
      "Hamburg",
      "Frankfurt"
    ],
    "category": "geography",
    "difficulty": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the classic game where players take turns placing black and white stones in an attempt to capture areas of the board?",
    "right_answer": "Go",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Scrabble",
      "Chess",
      "Clue"
    ],
    "category": "sport_and_leisure",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these holidays is celebrates the Jewish New Year?",
    "right_answer": "Rosh Hashanah",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Yom Kippur",
      "Hanukkah",
      "Passover"
    ],
    "category": "society_and_culture",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "Which actor did the voice-over on the Michael Jackson song 'Thriller'?",
    "right_answer": "Vincent Price",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Bela Lugosi",
      "Christopher Lee",
      "Boris Karloff"
    ],
    "category": "music",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the fictional company owned by Batman?",
    "right_answer": "Wayne Enterprises",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Superhero Inc.",
      "Gotham Corp.",
      "The Dark Knight Co."
    ],
    "category": "film_and_tv",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the capital city of Turkmenistan?",
    "right_answer": "Ashgabat",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Lusaka",
      "Antananarivo",
      "Addis Ababa"
    ],
    "category": "geography",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "In 1993, which famous singer co-patented a pair of shoes that provided a \"Method and means for creating anti-gravity illusion\"?",
    "right_answer": "Michael Jackson",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Prince",
      "Madonna",
      "Jamiroquai"
    ],
    "category": "society_and_culture",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "Which bay is marked by Cape Charles and Cape Henry in Virginia, on its northern and southern sides?",
    "right_answer": "Chesapeake Bay",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "San Francisco Bay",
      "Hudson Bay",
      "Tampa Bay"
    ],
    "category": "geography",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these is an American Football team based in New Orleans?",
    "right_answer": "New Orleans Saints",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "New Orleans Flames",
      "New Orleans Dolphins",
      "New Orleans Cardinals"
    ],
    "category": "sport_and_leisure",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "What city is the smallest in the United States to have an NFL franchise?",
    "right_answer": "Green Bay",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Buffalo",
      "Jacksonville",
      "San Diego"
    ],
    "category": "sport_and_leisure",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "In which country is the city of Auckland?",
    "right_answer": "New Zealand",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Australia",
      "Ireland",
      "Canada"
    ],
    "category": "geography",
    "difficulty": 1
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the plot of the movie The Treasure of the Sierra Madre?",
    "right_answer": "Two men searching for work in 1920s Mexico convince an old prospector to help them mine for gold.",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Historical events unfold from the perspective of an Alabama man with an IQ of 75.",
      "A skilled forger and conman is pursued by an FBI agent.",
      "After his son is captured and taken to Sydney, a clownfish sets out on a journey to bring him home."
    ],
    "category": "film_and_tv",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "Chiwetel Ejiofor plays the role of which character in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?",
    "right_answer": "Karl Mordo",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Odin",
      "Tony Stark",
      "Thor"
    ],
    "category": "film_and_tv",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these is an American Football team based in New York?",
    "right_answer": "New York Jets",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "New York Jaguars",
      "New York Saints",
      "New York Kraken"
    ],
    "category": "sport_and_leisure",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A freed slave sets out to rescue his wife from a brutal plantation-owner.'",
    "right_answer": "Django Unchained",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Leon",
      "Gran Torino",
      "Monty Python and the Holy Grail"
    ],
    "category": "film_and_tv",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the more common term for a person from Nevada?",
    "right_answer": "Nevadan",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Nevadite",
      "Nevadien",
      "Nevadanian"
    ],
    "category": "society_and_culture",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "In which of Shakespeare's plays does the character 'Prospero' appear?",
    "right_answer": "The Tempest",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Othello",
      "A Midsummer Night's Dream",
      "Romeo and Juliet"
    ],
    "category": "arts_and_literature",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these countries borders People's Republic of China?",
    "right_answer": "Laos",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Bangladesh",
      "Thailand",
      "Cambodia"
    ],
    "category": "geography",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "Where in the world are parsnips originally from?",
    "right_answer": "Europe",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Central America",
      "China",
      "Central Asia"
    ],
    "category": "food_and_drink",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "Which influential historical person sought to reform the Roman Catholic Church - starting the Protestant Reformation?",
    "right_answer": "Martin Luther",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Asoka",
      "Louis Daguerre",
      "Gregor Mendel"
    ],
    "category": "society_and_culture",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "What sport would you associate with The Indianapolis 500?",
    "right_answer": "Motorsports",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Athletics",
      "Golf",
      "Cycling"
    ],
    "category": "sport_and_leisure",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "Of which country did Robert Menzies become Prime Minister in April 1939?",
    "right_answer": "Australia",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Canada",
      "The United Kingdom",
      "New Zealand"
    ],
    "category": "history",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the capital city of United Arab Emirates?",
    "right_answer": "Abu Dhabi",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Rabat",
      "Meccah",
      "Islamabad"
    ],
    "category": "geography",
    "difficulty": 3
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these adjectives means \"close to fainting or lightheaded\"?",
    "right_answer": "Woozy",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Parched",
      "Zealous",
      "Nauseous"
    ],
    "category": "general_knowledge",
    "difficulty": 2
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the capital of Congo?",
    "right_answer": "Brazzaville",
    "wrong_answers": [
      "Conakry",
      "Dakar",
      "Nairobi"
    ],
    "category": "geography",
    "difficulty": 3
  }
]